Guide to the Jody Jones Hunter and Sian McLain Hunter Collection of Works by Peter Taylor, 1946-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Jody Jones Hunter and Sian McLain Hunter Collection of Works by Peter Taylor 1946-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Hunter, Jody Jones.
1.0 Linear Feet 100 Items
Peter Matthew Hillsman Taylor (8 January 1917-2 November 1994) was an American author and writer.
Collection includes periodical and print publications with writings by and about Taylor, clippings of reviews and obituaries, and a small amount of manuscript material.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Jody Jones Hunter and Sian McLain Hunter Collection of Works by Peter Taylor were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2010. Many items were removed for individual cataloging.
Biographical Note
Peter Matthew Hillsman Taylor (8 January 1917-2 November 1994) was an American author and writer. He was born in Trenton, Tennessee, and lived with his family in Missouri as a child before attending high school in Memphis. Taylor attended college at Southwestern and Vanderbilt before graduating from Kenyon College in 1940. In addition to his writing career, Taylor was also a professor at the Woman's College of the University of North Carolina (now UNC Greensboro), Kenyon College, Ohio State University, and the University of Virginia. He was married to poet Eleanor Ross Taylor.
Taylor's works included short stories, plays, and three novels: A Woman of Means (1950), A Summons to Memphis (1986; winner of the Pulitzer Prize), and In the Tennessee Country (1994).
Collection Overview
Collection includes periodical and print publications with writings by and about Taylor, clippings of reviews and obituaries, and a small amount of manuscript material. The majority of the collection consists of literary journals with stories, plays, or poems by Taylor, including issues of The Kenyon Review, The Virginia Quarterly Review, and The Sewanee Review. One manuscript item of note is the first typescript page of In The Tennessee Country, heavily corrected in pencil in Taylor's hand.
Many items were removed for individual cataloging.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Taylor, Peter, 1917-1994
Hunter, Jody Jones
Hunter, Sian McLain
Taylor, Peter, 1917-1994 -- In the Tennessee Country
Authors, American -- 20th century
American literature -- Southern States -- History and criticism
Detailed Description of Collection
- Peter Taylor materials, 1946-1994, (1 box)
  - Taylor's writings in periodicals (Box 1)
    - There (story) in The Kenyon Review, Vol. XXVI, No. 1., Winter 1964.
    - "A Stand in the Mountains" (play) in The Kenyon Review, Vol. XXX, No. 2, 1968.
    - "Dean of Men" (story) in The Virginia Quarterly Review, Vol. 45, No 2., Spring 1969.
    - "Daphne's Lover" (story) in The Sewanee Review, Vol. LXXVII, No. 2, Spring 1969.
      Also contains a poem by Eleanor Ross Taylor.
    - "The Whistler" (play) in The Virginia Quarterly Review, Vol. 46, No. 2., Spring 1970.
    - "Three Plays" in The Sewanee Review, Vol. LXXX, No. 2, April-June 1972.
    - "The Early Guest" (play) in Shenandoah, Vol. XXIV, No. 2, Winter 1973.
      Also contains "An Interview with Peter Taylor" by Stephen Goodwin, and a story ("Spending") by Anne Tyler.
    - "His Other Life," "Peach Trees Gone Wild in the Lane," and "The Megalopolitans" (poems) in Ploughshares, Vol. 2, No. 4, 1975
      Also contains 2 poems by Eleanor Ross Taylor.
    - "Three Heroines" (story-poem) in The Virginia Quarterly Review, Vol. 51, No 2., Spring 1975.
  - Periodicals about Taylor
    - "A Garland for Peter Taylor on His Sixtieth Birthday," special issue of Shenandoah, Vol. XXVIII, No. 2., Winter 1977.
    - "PW Interviews Peter Taylor," in Publisher's Weekly, 18 January 1985.
  - Taylor's writings in books
    - "The Old Forest" (story) in William Abrahams' Prize Stories 1980: The O. Henry Awards. Garden City, NY: Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1980.
  - Books about Taylor
    - Robison, James C. Peter Taylor: A Study of the Short Fiction. Boston: Twayne Publishers, 1988.
  - Manuscripts and miscellaneous
    - First page of the original typescript of Taylor's last novel, In the Tennessee Country
      Heavily corrected in pencil in Taylor's hand, with his initialled heading "from new novel. PT. September 16, 1987."
    - Photocopies of 7 letters from Taylor to Robie Macauley, 1946-1948
    - Clippings: Reviews, 1984-1994
    - Clippings: Obituaries, 1994
    - Miscellaneous